Guide to the Achilles Fang Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Achilles Fang papers
1947-1958
YCAL MSS 99
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.26
(5 boxes)
The Achilles Fang Papers document the professional and personal relationship between Achilles Fang and Ezra Pound. The papers consist of correspondence and writings, most of which date from between 1950 and 1954. The correspondence principally concerns Fang's efforts to assist Pound in the transliteration of Chinese characters and in the publication of his Confucian translations. Writings include galley proofs of and Fang's introduction to Pound's The Classic Anthology as Defined by Confucious. The bulk of the writings are drafts of Fang's doctoral dissertation, Material for the Study of Pound's Cantos.
Fang, Achilles
Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Ilse M. Fang on the Ezra Pound Fund, 1997. Gift of Ilse M. Fang, 1997.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Achilles Fang (1910-1995)
Achilles Fang, sinologist and comparatist. At Harvard University, Fang wrote his 1958 doctoral disseration entitled "Material for the Study of Pound's Cantos " and became friendly with Pound in the process. Fang became Pound's primary correspondent and source on Chinese topics, assisting Pound with his translation work on The Classic Anthology as Defined by Confucious.
Scope and Contents
The Achilles Fang Papers document the professional and personal relationship between Achilles Fang and Ezra Pound. The papers consist of correspondence and writings, most of which date from between 1950 and 1954. The correspondence principally concerns Fang's efforts to assist Pound in the transliteration of Chinese characters and in the publication of his Confucian translations. Writings include galley proofs of and Fang's introduction to Pound's The Classic Anthology as Defined by Confucious. The bulk of the writings are drafts of Fang's doctoral dissertation, "Material for the Study of Pound's Cantos ."
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Correspondence, 1947-1958. II. Writings, 1954-1956.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Chinese language -- Translating; Shi jing; Fang, Achilles; Pound, Dorothy; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; Pound, Omar S., 1926-
- Correspondence, 1947-1958, undated; Series I; 0.84; (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Letters to Fang from various individuals.
  - Laughlin, James, 1950, undated (Box 1)
  - Pound, Ezra, 1950-1952; 18 (Box 1)
  - Pound, Ezra, 1953-1958; 17 (Box 2)
    Includes letters to Fang from Omar and Dorothy Pound regarding the advisability of a 1955 petition for Pound's release from St. Elizabeth's hospital.
  - Notes on Chinese language and literature sent to Fang by Pound, 1947, undated; 2 (Box 2)
- Writings, 1954-1956, undated; Series II; 2.42; (3 boxes)
  - The Classic Anthology as Defined by Confucious, translated by Ezra Pound. Galley proof with corrections by Pound and Fang, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Introduction to The Classic Anthology as Defined by Confucious, by Achilles Fang. Typescript, 1954-1956 (Box 3)
    Includes notes by Fang
  - "Material for the Study of Pound's Cantos ," by Fang. Typescript, annotated, 1958; 15 (Box 3)
  - "Material for the Study of Pound's Cantos ," by Fang. Typescript, annotated, 1958; 25 (Box 4)
  - "Material for the Study of Pound's Cantos ," by Fang. Typescript, annotated, 1958; 12 (Box 5)
  - "Preliminary Survey," unidentified author. Typescript with handwritten and typescript notes, undated (Box 5)
  - The Asian Student, includes review of The Classic Anthology as Defined by Confucious, 1954 September 21 (Box 5)